A Guide to the Correspondence and subject files of the Commissioner of the Virginia Dept. of Labor and Industry, 1947-2010
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and subject files of the Commissioner of the Virginia Dept. of Labor and Industry, 1947-2010
The Library of Virginia
33939, 33972, 34434, 34698, 35638, 37903, 41036, 42488, 50380
52 cu. ft. (52 boxes)
Virginia Dept. of Labor and Industry. Commissioner.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years (Code of Virginia 42.1-78).
Acquisition Information
Dept. of Labor and Industry, transferred and accessioned 20 June 1991.
Biographical Information
The Dept. of Labor and Industry has its origins in the Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statistics, which was created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 3, 1898. The General Assembly saw a need for an agency to compile and circulate data on the industrial pursuits of the state as they related to the commercial, industrial, social, educational, and sanitary condition of the laboring classes and to the permanent prosperity of the productive industries of the state. The name of the Bureau was changed to the Bureau of Labor and Industry on February 13, 1924.
Several divisions were added to the bureau to deal with a variety of labor related issues. The Division of Mines and Quarries was created in 1912 (duties of this division transferred to the newly created Dept. of Mines, Minerals and Energy in 1985) and joined the Division of Factory Inspection as a unit with the Bureau. In 1922 The Division of Women and Children was created to enforce child labor laws, the 10 hour work day limit and regulate issues related to the employment of women. The Division of State Public Employment Service was created in 1926 to help connect people seeking jobs and employers seeking workers (this division was eliminated in 1960 with the creation of the Virginia Employment Commission).
The state government reorganization act of April 18, 1927 changed the name of the bureau to the Dept. of Labor and Industry and gave it the status of a regular administrative agency of the state. The governor appoints a commissioner, subject to confirmation by the General Assembly, who exercises supervision and control of the department. Several additional divisions were created in the department: Division of Apprenticeship Training (1938), Division of Factory, Institution and Mercantile Inspection (1951 - in 1967 this becomes the Division of Construction Safety Inspection and the Division of Industrial Safety), Advisory Council on Industrial Safety (1951), Safety Codes Commission (1962 - which later becomes the Safety and Health Codes Board), Division of OSHA Voluntary Compliance and Training (1977), Division of State Labor Law Administration (1978), Bureau of Occupational Health (1985 - transferred from Virginia Dept. of Health).
Commissioners of the Dept. of Labor and Industry include: Archer P. Montague, 1898-1899; James B. Doherty, 1900-1917; C.G. Kizer, 1917-1918; John Hirschberg, 1919-1920; John Hopkins Hall, Jr., 1921-1937; Thomas B. Morton, 1938-1941; John Hopkins Hall, Jr., 1942-1949; Edmond M. Boggs, 1949-1977; Robert F. Beard, 1977-1982; Azie Taylor Morton, 1982-1983; Eva S. Teig, 1983-1985; Carol A. Amato, 1985-1994; Theron J. Bell, 1994-1998; John Mills Barr, 1998-2000; Jeffrey D. Brown 2000-2002; and C. Ray Davenport, 2002-2010; Courtney Malveaux, 2010-2013; and C. Ray Davenport, 2014 -.
The Dept. of Labor and Industry's primary responsibility is the administering and enforcing of occupational safety and occupational health activities in both the public and private sectors. The mission of the Dept. is to make Virginia a better place to work by promoting safe and healthful workplaces, best employment practices, and job training opportunities. The Dept. provides Virginians with a broad variety of services to employers and workers that range from workplace safety, assistance to companies in establishing apprenticeships, to collecting unpaid wages for workers.
Scope and Content
This series consists of the incoming and outgoing correspondence of the Commissioner of the Dept. of Labor and Industry; reports, project files, and subject files also included. This series documents the administrative activities of the agency, as well as the establishment of policy and procedures, and major achievements of the agency.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Correspondence and subject files, 1947-1983 [Accession 33939]
Series II: Correspondence and subject files, 1985-1987 [Accession 33972]
Series III: Correspondence and subject files, 1982-1989 [Accession 34434]
Series IV: Correspondence and subject files, 1977-1990 [Accession 34698]
Series V: Correspondence and subject files, 1971-1992 [Accession 35638]
Series VI: Correspondence and subject files, 1986-1997 [Accession 37903]
Series VII: Correspondence and subject files, 1989-2000 [Accession 41036]
Series VIII: Correspondence and subject files, 1983-2002 [Accession 42488]
Series IX: Correspondence and subject files, 1972-2010 [Accession 50380]
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence and subject files [Accession 33939], 1947-1983., Extent: 9 cu. ft. (9 boxes). (Box 1-9)
  - Virginia Public Utility Act, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility strikes since passage of Act, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Public Utility mediation, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Arbitration and mediation, File 1, 1962-1975 (Box 2)
  - Arbitration and mediation, File 2, 1975-1980 (Box 2)
  - Elections, Utility and non-utility, 1954-1980 (Box 2)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Activities of Dept. of Labor and Industry, 1953-1969 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Advisory Council on the Virginia Economy, 1948-1959 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Bills - Sessions of General Assembly - Misc. correspondence, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Boiler and Pressure Vessel Board, 1972-1974 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Civil Defense, 1968-1971 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Clarke, Andrew W. litigation, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Commerce and Resources, Secretary of, 1973-1977 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Correspondence, 1953-1989 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Environmental Goals Task Force, 1972-1974 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, General Assembly, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Governor's Office, 1954-1976 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Grants, 1973-1976 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, IAGLO (International Association of Governmental Labor Officials), 1950 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Labor Laws of Virginia, 1960-1962 (Box 3)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Occupational Safety and Health, 1948-1978 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Radiation Safety and Health Standards, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Research and Drafting, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Right to Work Law, 1947-1973 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Right to Work Law, 1974-1980 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Safety and Health Regulations, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Statistical Program for Labor and Industry, Development of, 1952-1972 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1957-1959 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, U. S. Congress, Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1951-1977 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, U.S. District Court, Helmuth Scherer vs. John A. Cosgrove, et. al, 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Virginia Advisory Council on Industrial Safety, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Virginia Code Commission, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Virginia Manufacturing Association, 1964-1974 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Wage Division, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Westinghouse Electric Corporation, 1962-1967 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Women and Children's Division (now State Labor Law Administration), 1952-1974 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Edmond M. Boggs files, Women and Children's Division (now State Labor Law Administration), 1975-1983 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Agency agreements and evaluations, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Audit files, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Commerce and Resources, Secretary of, 1977-1979 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Commerce and Resources, Secretary of, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Commerce and Resources, Secretary of, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Economic Development and Activities, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Energy program, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Executive Branch of State Government Survey Resolution No. 9, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Field Offices, 1974-1984 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Governor's Office, 1979-1982 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Handicapped, 1974-1979 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Labor Law Division, 1978-1983 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Management team, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Misc., 1977-1982 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, OSHA Study Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Personnel, Miscellaneous, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Photographs, 1971-1981 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Regulations - Governor's Regulatory Reform Process - Miner's Regulations, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Safety, 1978-1983 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, Virginia Executive Institute, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Robert F. Beard files, VPI and Dept. of Labor and Industry Memorandum of Agreement, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, AFL-CIO, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Attorney General, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Annual report, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Audit file, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Auditor of Public Accounts, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Boiler and Pressure Vessel, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Commerce and Resources, Secretary of, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Complaints, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Dislocated Workers Program, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Freedom of Information, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Governor's Office, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Grants, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Legislation, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Mail, 1982-1984 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Memo of Agreement, VEC - DLI, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Miscellaneous correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Moving expenses, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, OSHA, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, People to People International, 1980-1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Personnel, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Proposed Safety and Health Advisory Committee, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Quarterly reports, 1981-1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, Regulatory Reform Advisory Board, Governor's Office, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Azie Taylor Morton files, VOSH Support position, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Administrative Process Act, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, AFL-CIO, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Agency agreements, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Agency agreements, 1984-1986 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Apprenticeships, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Arlington County, Virginia, and Virginia OSHA, 1980-1984 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Asbestos, 1983-1985 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Attorney General, 1950-1984 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Boiler and Pressure Vessel, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Byssinosis (Cotton dust), 1981-1986 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Commerce and Resources, Secretary of, 1983-1985 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Complaints, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Executive agreement, 1984-1986 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Fire sprinkler system and asbestos removal, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Fourth Street Office building, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Governor's Office, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Governor's Regulatory Reform Advisory Board, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Grants, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Health, Division of Occupational, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Information Technology, Dept. of, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Initiatives, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Labor law, 1983-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Legislation, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Memorandum of Understanding, 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Miscellaneous correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, NAGLO (National Association of Governmental Labor Officials), 1981-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, OSHA, 1983-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, OSHA Sub-Committee meeting, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Personnel, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Research and statistics, 1981-1983 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Safety week, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Schneider, Richard F., 1980-1984 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Staff meetings, 1982-1984 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Voluntary compliance, 1981-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, VOSH, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, VOSH Evaluation Task Forces, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, VPI, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Commissioner Eva S. Teig files, Water Control Board, 1984 (Box 8)
  - OSHA, State Plan Statistics, 1977 (Box 9)
  - OSHA, Statement on HR 14816-S. 2864, 1968 (Box 9)
  - OSHA, State Plan Virginia, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Division of Research and Statistics, Virginia Dept. of Labor and Industry, Publications, 1968 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, First Semi-Annual Evaluation, October 1976 - March 1977 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Second Semi-Annual Evaluation, April 1977 - September 1977 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Third Semi-Annual Evaluation, October 1977 - March 1978 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Fourth Semi-Annual Report, April - September 1978 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Fifth Evaluation, October 1978 - September 1979 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Sixth Evaluation, October 1979 - September 1980 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Seventh Evaluation, October 1980 - September 1981 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Eighth Evaluation, October 1981 - September 1982 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Evaluation October 1982 - March 1985 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Evaluation, April 1984 - December 1985 (Box 9)
  - VOSH, State of Virginia, Evaluation, January - December 1986 (Box 9)
- Series II: Correspondence and subject files [Accession 33972], 1985-1987., Extent: 2 cu. ft. (2 boxes). (Box 1-2)
  - Agreements - Housing and Community Development, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - AFL-CIO, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Apprenticeship - IASG development, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Apprenticeship - Miscellaneous, 1987 and prior (Box 1)
  - Apprenticeship - Miscellaneous, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Apprenticeship - Regulatory review - Numeric Ratio - Apprenticeship to Journeymen, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Apprenticeship - Regulatory review - Program Sponsorship and evaluation procedures, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Asbestos, 1987 and prior (Box 1)
  - Boiler and Pressure Valve Division, 1987 and prior (Box 1)
  - Center on Environmental Health, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Commerce and Resources, Secretary of, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Complaints, Strikes, etc., 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Economic Development, Secretary of, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Employment Commission, Virginia, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - EEO, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Field Sanitation, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Field Sanitation, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Study, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Fourth Street Office Building, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - GAO Panel - Washington, DC, 1987 December 3 (Box 1)
  - General Services, Dept. of, 1987 and prior (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Grants, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Hazard Communication, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Hazard Communication, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Health, Division of Occupational, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Information Technology, Dept. of, 1987 and prior (Box 2)
  - Internal Audit/Evaluation System Project, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Labor Law Division, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Labor, U.S. Dept. of, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Legislation, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Masonry Contractors Association, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Memoranda of Understanding - Miscellaneous, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - NAGLO, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - OSHA, 1986 and prior (Box 2)
  - OSHA, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Personnel - Miscellaneous, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Research and Statistics, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Radford Arsenal, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Safety in the workplace, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - SCRRRAP (Paperwork Reduction), 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Superfund, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Supervisors meetings (REVIEW), 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Surry Nuclear Plant, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Transportation, Dept. of, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Unionization of State Employees, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - VOSH, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Virginia Society of Professional Engineers, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - VOC/Technical Education Coordination Council, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Voluntary Compliance, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
- Series III: Correspondence and subject files [Accession 34434], 1982-1989., Extent: 2 cu. ft. (2 boxes). (Box 1-2)
  - Amusement rides, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
  - Attorney General's Office, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Authorized signature, 1984-1988 (Box 1)
  - Batman Corporation, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Boiler and Pressure Vessel, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Bunker Hill Foods, 1989 (Box 1)
  - "Code" Commission, Virginia, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Contracts, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Consolidated Laboratory Services, Division of, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Employers meeting, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Financial, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Grants, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Hazard Communication, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Human Rights Act, Virginia, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Immigration, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Job Training and Partnership Act, 1982-1988 (Box 1)
  - Labor Law, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Legislation, 1989 (Box 1)
  - March of Dimes, 1989 (Box 1)
  - J.G. Miller, Inc., 1989 (Box 1)
  - NAGLO (National Association of Governmental Labor Officials), 1988 (Box 1)
  - Office equipment, 1984-1987 (Box 2)
  - OSHA, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - OSHSPA (Occupational Safety and Health State Plan Association), 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Personnel, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Personnel and Training, Dept. of, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Pittston Company, Strike, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Safety Enforcement, 1986-1989 (Box 2)
  - Scanning, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Southeastern Virginia Training Center, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - State cars, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Union meeting, 1988 (Box 2)
  - United Way campaign, 1987-1989 (Box 2)
  - VOSH, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Washington Design Group, Ltd., Building Program Study, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
- Series IV: Correspondence and subject files [Accession 34698], 1977-1990., Extent: 4.35 cu. ft. (5 boxes). (Box 1-5)
  - Apprenticeship, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Apprenticeship, State JAC, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Apprenticeship related instruction, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Apprenticeship, Transfer of related instruction, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Accounts receivable study, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Administration, Division of, 1990 (Box 1)
  - AFL - CIO, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Asbestos, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Attorney General's Office, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Boiler and Pressure Vessel Operators Certification Standard Task Force, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Boiler and Pressure Vessel Training Study, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1988-1990 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Combined charities, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Federal Liaison and Technical Support, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Field Office Correspondence, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Health Department, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Health Enforcement, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Healthtex Corporation, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Insurance, 1987-1989 (Box 2)
  - Labor Force Needs of the 1990s Taskforce (Box 2)
  - Labor Law, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Manslaughter Policy, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Accidents, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Apprenticeship, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Apprenticeship, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Asbestos, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Asbestos, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Attorney General's Office, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Confined Space, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Economic Development, Secretary of, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Economic Development, Secretary of, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Governor's Office, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Labor Law Division, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Legislation, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Legislative proposal package, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Legislative studies, 1989 (Box 3)
  - National Governor's Association, 1984-1989 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1989 (Box 3)
  - OSHA, 1988 (Box 3)
  - OSHPA (Occupational Safety and Health State Plan Association), 1989 (Box 4)
  - Personnel, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Procurement Study Task Force, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Reorganization, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Resumes, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Safety and Health Codes Board, 1986-1989 (Box 2)
  - Sanitation Standard Task Force, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Senate Bill 393, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - Speeches, 1977-1982 (Box 4)
  - Speeches, 1983-1989 (Box 4)